

Guilherme Morone Araujo

Nationality: Brazilian Date of birth: 10/02/2001 Gender: Male

Email: guimorone@gmail.com in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/guimorone

Website: https://guimorone.github.io

ABOUT MYSELF

Originally from Rio but now based in Recife, I've had the privilege of growing up in two vibrant cities. My passions are as diverse as my background, ranging from an avid love for games and books to an insatiable curiosity for travel and technology. Furthermore, I am always eager to explore new opportunities and challenges that can help me grow both as a professional and as a person, fueled by my passion for learning and applying new technologies to solve real-world problems.

I have been working on Software Development since 2022. Not only that, but I am used to developing Big Data applications that demand high efficiency, scalability, and low cost. All my projects demanded skills in web development, data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing, in order to deliver quality solutions to clients.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Neurotech [10/04/2024 - Current]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://www.neurotech.com.br | Email: guilherme.morone@neurotech.com.br | Na me of unit/department: Hydra - Neurolake - Business/sector: Financial and insurance activities

Full-time job:

- In general, using skills in backend development (FastAPI), data engineering, Terraform, Git, Airflow and cloud computing (AWS).
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Ensure high-quality, scalable application development.
- \bullet Using Amazon Web Services such as Lambda, DynamoDB, EC2, Athena, S3 and more.

Software Engineer

Jalan [10/04/2024 - 31/05/2024]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://jalan.com.br

Full-time job:

• Worked as a Full Stack developer using Vue.js and Quasar along with Python and Lambda Functions (AWS).

Mobile Engineer

aca.so [01/03/2024 - 31/03/2024]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://aca.so

Freelancer:

• Worked as a Mobile Engineer in a project (aca.so mobile app) using React Native.

Full Stack Developer

[01/07/2023 - 28/12/2023]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

- Website made with 3 more colleagues to an external customer.
- The main purpose is to identify bank check fields easily, so you do not have to type manually.
- The bank check OCR is based on our customer's API, we did not implement it, just the website.
- It also offers API Integration, history download and other features.
- Developed using React, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS and Django (Python).

Software Engineer

Oncase [01/02/2022 - 28/12/2023]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://www.oncase.com.br

Full-time job:

- Developed Big Data applications with a focus on high efficiency, scalability, and low cost.
- Developed frontend applications using React (JavaScript, TypeScript and HTML/CSS) and Redux.
- Implemented backend functionality using Python frameworks Flask and Django.
- Implemented effective CI/CD pipelines for seamless integration and deployment through Docker and GitHub Actions.
- In general, utilized skills in web development (Django, React and HTML/CSS), data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Enhanced customer relationships through the delivery of top-notch solutions.
- Ensured high-quality and scalable application development.
- · Hosted applications on Google Cloud Platform using Cloud Run and Artifact Registry.
- Utilized Amazon Web Services for hosting, leveraging services like Amplify, Route53, and Lambda.

Mobile Engineer

InSpace [01/08/2022 – 31/10/2022]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://inspace.tech

Freelancer:

• Identification of objects (censored specificity) from a mobile camera for legal purposes.

Game Developer

Educandus [01/06/2021 – 31/10/2021]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://educandus.com.br

Internship:

• I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

Game Developer

Educandus [01/05/2020 - 30/12/2020]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://educandus.com.br

Internship:

• I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor in Computer Engineering

Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) [01/02/2019 – 31/08/2024]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://portal.cin.ufpe.br | Field(s) of study: Information and Communication
Technologies (ICTs): • Software and applications development and analysis • Computer use • Database and network design and administration • Information and communication technologies not elsewhere classified • Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs) not further defined; Engineering, manufacturing and construction: • Electronics and automation | Final grade: 9.03/10.0 | Level in EQF: EQF level 6

Student Teaching Assistant

Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) [01/06/2022 - 31/03/2024]

Website: https://portal.cin.ufpe.br | Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs): ● Software and applications development and analysis

- Dedicated Student Teaching Assistant in the field of Software and Systems Engineering.
- Provided invaluable support to students in software development and requirements engineering, with a primary goal of crafting top-tier applications of exceptional quality.

The Complete Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart

Udemy [15/03/2024 – 03/04/2024]

Website: https://udemy.com

Link: https://ude.my/UC-3fd9599a-bff2-4960-8d34-dbb3b41ced55

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Data, ML, and Al in Google Cloud - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost [01/03/2023 - 14/03/2023]

Website: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/badges/3311200?

<u>utm_medium=social&utm_source=linkedin&utm_campaign=ql-social-share</u>

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Infrastructure in Google Cloud - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost [01/03/2023 - 13/03/2023]

Website: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/badges/3303084

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Networking

Google Cloud Skills Boost [01/03/2023 - 13/03/2023]

Website: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/badges/3305980

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Cloud Computing Fundamentals - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost [01/03/2023 - 12/03/2023]

Website: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/badges/3302433

The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

Udemy [01/04/2020 - 21/04/2020]

Website: https://udemy.com

Link: https://ude.my/UC-5d594204-a414-4cb1-a388-72e3daf7c1c6

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

English German

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C2 LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Digital Skills - Test Results			
	Information and data literacy	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
	Communication and collaboration	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
0	Digital content creation	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
	Safety	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
	Problem solving	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6

Results from a self-assessment based on The Digital Competence Framework 2.1

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Games

Reading Books

Travelling

Gym

Movies